{
    "id": "fa0ba0bb5beb48b88f0b6a50882ff86f",
    "title": "Tenses Quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ................................ there for two hours and then I went home.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "waited",
                "have waited",
                "had waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2eb6fbaa4e924f9a8e2a5005b16257fa"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ..................................... six novels so far.",
            "description": "We often use the present perfect to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "wrote",
                "has written",
                "had written"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9d49e3b970dc4c0e9e0b949c709a189c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ....................................... from Las Vegas yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "returned",
                "has returned",
                "had returned"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ebe2bf2236bd4ea6a11c5c101ba93899"
        },
        {
            "question": "See that you .................................... no harm.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cause",
                "have caused",
                "caused"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0273d90b130d47f98f4ad0368b8ad724"
        },
        {
            "question": "The hostess made sure that the guests .................................... enough to eat and drink.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "have",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9be5b4a5c4ac42c989f87dfd03709473"
        },
        {
            "question": "You will get the job if you ................................................ in the interview.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "succeed",
                "succeeded",
                "had succeeded"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "475691fe9e444dba8aaf90a7a8359393"
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor concluded that the man ...................................... several hours ago.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "has died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2846d98753b849c6b6b921784e52fadf"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ............................................ to hear from him for more than two weeks now.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "are waiting",
                "have been waiting",
                "waited"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "35646c43f45e4a32a46ea4977d1363c3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The show ....................................... by the time we reached the theatre.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "began",
                "has begun",
                "had begun"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "47ffad8200324366941c4b78a81b6289"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ..................................... for work at",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits and routines. ",
            "answers": [
                "leaves",
                "is leaving",
                "will leave"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2fe4c9713bf64c2da3537367a9ea8c7c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Father .................................... the newspaper every morning.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits and routines. ",
            "answers": [
                "reads",
                "is reading",
                "has read"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9bb0d7a4ae3b48288987d26b79a6fd76"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I visited him he ........................................ bed-ridden for months.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that continued up to a certain point of time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "had been",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d70716cda33847ee99b871ae2eb7d78b"
        }
    ]
}